Samuel Jacobo Garavito Segura

Python Engineer

Profile

Computer scientist with professional focus on software development with two years of experience in integrated business automation. I use Python to design automated solutions to increase quality, accuracy, agility and optimization of operational and business processes. My work encompasses the administration of data source systems, as well as automation of data flow, ETL pipelines, and reporting.

Areas of Expertise

Mathematics - Algorithm Design - Data Analysis - Data Visualization - Software Development - Version Control - Process Automation - IT Automation - Test Automation

Professional Experience

Data Specialist, in Teleperformance

Bogotá D.C, Colombia 11/2022 - present

- **Technological Transformation:** Facilitating the corporate technological transformation through the adoption of cutting-edge Python tools to automate reporting processes.
- Client Collaboration Management: Managing collaboration with a variety of clients such as Uber, Discord, Sony, and Bancolombia to provide reporting technological solutions.
- **Data Infrastructure Development:** Developing software to establish and maintain a robust data infrastructure, addressing aspects of data storage and transfer.
- **Software Solutions for Data Extraction:** Designing software aimed at extracting customer-specific data to generate reports in an automated way by accessing various sources such as REST APIs, web pages, databases and data warehouses.
- **Software Solutions for Data Processing:** Designing software solutions to clean, validate, filter and transform customer reports data in an automated way.

Python Developer, in Pidgin Contact Solutions

Bogotá D.C, Colombia 03/2022 - 11/2022

- Addressed data office challenges for Teleperformance client using Python.
- Provided comprehensive support for our web development environment, encompassing both testing and production environments.
- Distributed and scaled data management scripts within our web development environment.
- Developed robust regression automation suites and tests utilizing the Robot Framework for browser-based applications.
- Implemented effective algorithms to optimize data extraction, processing, and downloading processes, enhancing overall efficiency.

Online Courses & Certifications

- Data Analytics & Big Data (Jun. 2023) Cymetria Group S.A.S. AD&BD-202342
- Using Python to Interact with the Operating System (Feb. 2023) Google, Coursera
- Python Specialization (Dec. 2022) Michigan University, Coursera
- Introduction to control versioning with Git and GitHub (Apr. 2022) Andes University, Coursera
- Software Development Diploma (Oct. 2021) North University SO1OV2RUNGBREJG9TAY5

Education

BSc Computer Science in National University of Colombia

Bogotá D.C, Colombia 2018 - present

Professional profile with a solid background in Mathematics aimed at enhancing logical and abstract thinking, directed towards structured and detailed problem-solving through the use of algorithms alongside computational tools.

Skills

- Languages and Software: ₱ Python,
 JavaScript,
 HTML,
 CSS, SQL,

 R, SAS.
- Database Management Systems: SMySQL, PostgreSQL.
- Automation: Selenium, Robotframework, Pytest.
- Operating Systems: # Windows 🐧 Linux.
- Version Control: git Git G GitHub.
- Data Management: P NumPy, Pandas, SciPy, DuckDB Dplyr, Sqldf.
- Data Visualization: Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotnine Ggplot Microsoft Power BI, Microsoft Excel.
- Frameworks: 🕏 Flask, Django, FastAPI, Dash 🗦 Bootstrap.
- Soft Skills: Resilience, Adaptability, Teamwork, Productivity, Creative Problem-Solving, Logical Thinking.

Languages

• **Spanish** [Native]

• **English** [Professional]

References

Personal references

- Lucas Ibarra Sierra
 - **→** +57 3213438944
 - @ juanlucas2000@hotmail.com
 - **Engineer at Globant**

- La Nicolas Eduardo Gutierrez Meza
 - **J** +57 3013833841
 - @ nicolas.Gutierrez@co.ey.com
 - LT Consultant at EY

Work References

- Asley Nicole Mora
 - **J** +57 3053194579
 - @ nmora@pidgin.com.co
 - Pidgin Contact Solutions Manager

- A Nelson Reales Herrera
 - **J** +57 3023237198
 - @ realesherrera.5@nlsa.teleperformance.com
 - * Teleperformance's RPA Supervisor